{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["France","Spain","United States"],"question":"Which country is the world's largest producer of wine by volume?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Violin","incorrectAnswers":["Viola","Cello","Double Bass"],"question":"What is the name of the highest pitched stringed instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"L","incorrectAnswers":["R","H","J"],"question":"What is the Roman numeral for fifty?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Argentina ","incorrectAnswers":["Uruguay","Paraguay","Peru"],"question":"In what country is the most lowest (sea level) point of South America?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A Table Tennis Player","incorrectAnswers":["A Golfer","A Cricketer","A Baseball Player"],"question":"Who Might Use A Penholder Grip","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Angola","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Liberia","Nicaragua"],"question":"Luanda is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Bayeux Tapestry","incorrectAnswers":["The Hastings Tapestry","The Calais Tapestry","The Wynton Tapestry"],"question":"Which famous tapestry commemorates the Norman conquest of England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'And Then There Were None'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Los Angeles","incorrectAnswers":["New York","Chicago","Atlanta"],"question":"Bruce Willis spends Christmas fighting terrorists in the 1988 film 'Die Hard'', which American city is this set in","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Falafel","incorrectAnswers":["Ema Datshi","Succotash","Dholl Puri"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with The Middle East?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Van Morrison ","incorrectAnswers":["Megadeth","Boyz II Men","Janet Jackson"],"question":"Who released the album 'Tupelo honey'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Very Superior Old Pale","incorrectAnswers":["Very Special Origin Product","Very Serious On Palette","Very Secretive Order Produce"],"question":"What do the letters VSOP on a brandy bottle stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tiger Woods","incorrectAnswers":["Phil Mickelson","Arnold Palmer","Jack Nicklaus"],"question":"Who holds the record for all-time career earnings on the U.S. PGA circuit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vatican City","incorrectAnswers":["Moldova","Tuvalu","Vanuatu"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.va' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Baron in the Trees","incorrectAnswers":["Catch-22","The Big Sleep","The Sun Also Rises"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Cosimo Piovasco di Rondo'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Krona","incorrectAnswers":["Franc","Mark","Pund"],"question":"Before the Euro, what was the basic unit of currency for Iceland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Asia","North America","Europe"],"question":"What is the second largest continent in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Uruguay","incorrectAnswers":["Guyana","Uzbekistan","Paraguay"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.uy' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Harrison Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Brad Pitt","Michael Fassbender","John Cusack"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Star Wars and Blade Runner?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Kitten","incorrectAnswers":["An Eyas","A Cygnet","A Cria"],"question":"What is the word for a young cat?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hela","incorrectAnswers":["Aunt May Parker","The Collector","Pepper Potts"],"question":"Cate Blanchett plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"San Diego Padres","incorrectAnswers":["San Diego Celtics","San Diego Eagles","San Diego Bears"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in San Diego?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Italy","Peru"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Wulingyuan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Platoon","incorrectAnswers":["Children of a Lesser God","Hannah and Her Sisters","The Mission"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1986?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Back to the Future","incorrectAnswers":["The Truman Show","Raiders of the Lost Ark","Forrest Gump"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A high school student is sent thirty years into the past in a time-traveling car.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Fatal Attraction","incorrectAnswers":["Breakfast at Tiffany's","Grease","On the Waterfront"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Alex Forrest'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The median","incorrectAnswers":["The mean","The mode","The range"],"question":"What mathematical term refers to the middle number in a sequence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sequoyah","incorrectAnswers":["Geronimo","Sacagawea","Sitting Bull"],"question":"Who made reading and writing in the Cherokee language possible by creating a syllabary for it?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Spleen","incorrectAnswers":["Pancreas","Gallbladder","Appendix"],"question":"Which soft, purplish organ filters blood and stores platelets?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Eggplant","incorrectAnswers":["Cucumber","Avocado","Cauliflower"],"question":"What vegetable is traditionally used in moussaka, a Greek baked dish made with ground lamb or beef?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cordon Bleu","incorrectAnswers":["Sacre Bleu","Bleu du Fafa","Bleu Lundi"],"question":"What culinary term, often referring to a first-class cook, literally means 'Blue Ribbon'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Antoine de Saint-Exupéry","incorrectAnswers":["Alphonse Daudet","François-René de Chateaubriand","Victor Hugo"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Little Prince'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Doors","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Break On Through'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mojave","incorrectAnswers":["Apache","Navajo","Cherokee"],"question":"Which Native American tribe thrived in the scorching heat of the California desert that bears their name?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tasman","incorrectAnswers":["Zeelandic","Coral","Solomon"],"question":"Which sea is located between Australia and New Zealand?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Rhine ","incorrectAnswers":["The Danube","The Seine","The Elbe"],"question":"Which River Forms A Border Between France & Germany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Greed, for lack of a better word, is good.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Hello, gorgeous.\"","\"That’s a bingo!\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Wall Street'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jackie Onnasis","incorrectAnswers":["Jackie Starling","Jackie Middleton","Jackie Van der Steene"],"question":"What Was Jackie Kennedy's Name Before She Married John F Kennedy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["Vanuatu","Vienna","New Zealand"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.vn' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Spain","Portugal","Greece"],"question":"Which country is home to the cities of Taranto, Anzio, and Padua?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Smokey Mountains ","incorrectAnswers":["The Rockies","The Andes","The Black Mountains"],"question":"What mountains are located on the border of Tennessee & North Carolina?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Veal ","incorrectAnswers":["Beef","Pork","Lamb"],"question":"What type of meat is used in the preparation of Osso Bucco?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pacific","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantic","Indian","Arctic"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Ocean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon","Black","Yellow"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Portugal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"9","incorrectAnswers":["4","1","36"],"question":"How Many Gallons In A Firkin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Adele","incorrectAnswers":["Taylor Swift","Ed Sheeran","Beyoncé"],"question":"Released in 2008, which artist's debut album was titled \"19\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Shiva","incorrectAnswers":["Vishnu","Brihaspati","Krishna"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu god of destruction?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1955","incorrectAnswers":["1939","1947","1963"],"question":"In which year did the Vietnam war begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nine","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Three","Black"],"question":"What does the word 'nueve' mean in Spanish?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Augustus Caesar","incorrectAnswers":["Pontius Pilate","Tiberius","Caligula"],"question":"Who ruled Rome when Christ was born?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rango","incorrectAnswers":["Nemo","Simba","Po"],"question":"What 2011 animated film centers on a pet Chameleon who accidentally ends up in a lawless Wild West outpost?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Drum","incorrectAnswers":["Guitar","Viola","Tuba"],"question":"Which of these is a percussion instrument?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Mr. Brightside\" by The Killers","incorrectAnswers":["\"SpongeBob SquarePants Theme\" by Painty the Pirate","\"Hooked on a Feeling\" by B.J. Thomas","\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Coming out of my cage / And I've been doing just fine...\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Pawns","incorrectAnswers":["Bishops","Knights","Rooks"],"question":"Which chess piece is the most common?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Beggars Banquet'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Build-A-Bear","incorrectAnswers":["Teddy Bear Emporium","Toy Workshop","Plush Pals"],"question":"What is the name of the store where customers can build and customize their own stuffed animals?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Petri dish","incorrectAnswers":["Bunson burner","Erlenmeyer flask","Graduated cylinder"],"question":"What is the name for a shallow dish with a cover, used for science specimens?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Southeast Asia","Europe","India"],"question":"Where in the world are avocados originally from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Hungary","Austria"],"question":"In Which Country Was The Auschwitz Concentration Camp Located?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Third Man","incorrectAnswers":["The Usual Suspects","Mad Max","On the Waterfront"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Harry Lime'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Andy Serkis","incorrectAnswers":["Harrison Ford","Jack Nicholson","John Cusack"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Gollum in The Lord of the Rings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Oscar","incorrectAnswers":["Ordinary","Otter","Ombudsman"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter O?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sidney Poitier","incorrectAnswers":["Dustin Hoffman","Anthony Perkins","Anthony Hopkins"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Detective Virgil Tibbs in In the Heat of the Night?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Afghanistan","incorrectAnswers":["Malawi","Pakistan","Syria"],"question":"Kabul is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Uruguay","incorrectAnswers":["Peru","Ecuador","Suriname"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Argentina?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Pup","incorrectAnswers":["A Kit","A Gosling","A Poult"],"question":"What is the word for a young bat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Iron Maiden","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Squeeze"],"question":"Which English heavy metal band released the song 'The Number of the Beast'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the studio album 'Loud'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A banshee","incorrectAnswers":["A mermaid","A siren","A fairy"],"question":"In Gaelic folklore, what loud female spirit was believed to warn of a death?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pepper Potts","incorrectAnswers":["Valkyrie","Eitri","Wanda Maximoff"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Gwyneth Paltrow?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Fresh Prince","incorrectAnswers":["DJ Jazzy Jeff","Eminem","Jay Z"],"question":"What is Will Smith's Rapper Alter Ego?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Argle-bargle","incorrectAnswers":["Quomodocunquizing","Valetudinarian","Agastopia"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'copious but meaningless talk or writing'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ron Howard","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Apollo 13?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Abigail Breslin","incorrectAnswers":["Sally Hawkins","Lucy Lawless","Jacqueline Bisset"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Ghost Whisperer and Little Miss Sunshine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Onions","incorrectAnswers":["Broccoli","Cauliflower","Turnip"],"question":"What food makes your eyes water when cut?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Unicum","incorrectAnswers":["Bourbon","Becherovka","Pastis"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with Hungary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Rhine","incorrectAnswers":["The Amazon","The Seine","The Tiber"],"question":"Which river is Dusseldorf an important port on?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"All Quiet on the Western Front","incorrectAnswers":["The Big House","Disraeli","The Divorcee"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1930?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which band includes 'Björn Ulvaeus' as one of its members?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Daegu","incorrectAnswers":["Colombo","Singapore","Petaling Jaya"],"question":"Which of these cities is in South Korea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Reborn","incorrectAnswers":["Returned","Revolutionary","Respected"],"question":"The word \"renaissance\" comes from the Old French \"renaistre\", which means what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sic infit","incorrectAnswers":["Carpe diem","Amor vincit omnia","Faber est suae quisque fortunae"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases translates to 'So it begins'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ace Of Base","incorrectAnswers":["Modern Talking","The Cardigans","Every Little Thing"],"question":"Jenny & Lyn Beggren Are Singers With Which 90's Group","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Roman Empire","incorrectAnswers":["The Byzantine Empire","The Greek Empire","The Ottoman Empire"],"question":"Which Republic, which later turned full-blown empire, gained dominance over Italy around 274 B.C.?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Richard I","incorrectAnswers":["Richard III","James I","James III"],"question":"Who Was Known As \"Coeur De Lion\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1994","incorrectAnswers":["1986","1990","1998"],"question":"Pulp Fiction was released in which year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Guns N Roses","incorrectAnswers":["Sex Pistols","The Ramones","The Clash"],"question":"With Which Rock Band Does \"Slash\" Play Guitar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"To Kill A Mockingbird","incorrectAnswers":["The Big Sleep","The Wind in the Willows","The Sun Also Rises"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Arthur 'Boo' Radley'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Spinach","incorrectAnswers":["Pork","Mushroom","Lemon"],"question":"A food labelled 'Florentine' is likely to contain which ingredient?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Robert Hazard","incorrectAnswers":["Prince","Manfred Mann","David Bowie"],"question":"The song 'Girls Just Wanna Have Fun' was made popular by Cyndi Lauper, but who originally recorded it?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Liaquat Ali Khan","incorrectAnswers":["Benazir Bhutto","Nawaz Sharif","Zulfikar Ali Bhutto"],"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of Pakistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kramer vs. Kramer","incorrectAnswers":["All That Jazz","Apocalypse Now","Breaking Away"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1979?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"After graduating, a student gives his entire savings to charity and hitchhikes to Alaska.","incorrectAnswers":["A detective hired to expose an adulterer finds himself caught up in a web of deceit.","A general accuses soldiers of cowardice and their commanding officer must defend them.","A former neo-nazi tries to prevent his brother from going down the same path that he did."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Into the Wild?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Transformer","incorrectAnswers":["Resister","Capacitor","Micrometer"],"question":"What Electrical Device Can Change The Magnitude Of Voltage Or Current","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Partridge In A Pear Tree","incorrectAnswers":["5 Gold Rings","A Turtle Dove","True Love"],"question":"What did 'my true love give to me' on the first day of Christmas?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Origin","incorrectAnswers":["Axis","Intersection","Main Point"],"question":"What is the term used for the point (0,0) on a graph?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Radiohead","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Cream","Girls Aloud"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Kid A'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Haruki Murakami","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Umberto Eco","Søren Kierkegaard"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Blind Willow, Sleeping Woman'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly","incorrectAnswers":["Chinatown","Fast Times at Ridgemont High","The Silence of the Lambs"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Blondie'?","difficulty":"hard"},